# Sam Alexander Celani

github.com/alexander-the-alright • (810)683-4581 • sacelani@gmail.com

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Engineer with 5+ years of software development experience. Possess a bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering, with a strong focus on embedded programming. Looking to utilize my skills and knowledge in a new position in my field.

## **EDUCATION**

## Michigan Technological University - Houghton, MI

August 2014 - May 2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering Department GPA: **2.91** | Cumulative GPA: 2.87

**Outstanding Teaching Award** 

Member of Keweenaw Pride

## PROJECT EXPERIENCE

# Vice President, Wireless Communications Enterprise

Bird Sensor Team – **Project Engineer** 

- Created a low-cost, low-maintenance sensor to aid in a time study of bird strikes on windows
- Primarily in charge of programming (Arduino)

# **Project: Sentinel, Personal Project**

• Terminal-based Smart Home equivalent (Golang) and nodes (ESP8266)

# **Project: Soary!, Personal Project (WIP)**

• Terminal-based correspondence games of Sorry! (Golang)

### **Project: Ouotes, Personal Project**

• Terminal-based fun with networked programs, to get "random" MOTD on login (Golang)

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Whirlpool Corporation – Benton Harbor, MI

April 2022 – Present

# **Embedded Software Test Engineer**

- Conducted comprehensive testing of appliance connectivity across diverse product categories and software architectures
- Acquired proficiency with several in-house software tools for monitoring communications and flashing software
- Developed software tools on Raspberry Pi for router control to aid in automating tests, saving multiple workdays of manhours per software drop

# Pilot Systems International – Farmington Hills, MI

May 2021 – Feb 2022

## **Associate Systems Engineer**

- Wrote system and software level test scripts for a Vector HIL system
- Performed manual System of System testing using CANalyzer

# Advanced Power Systems Research Center – Calumet, MI

May – August 2018 and 2019

# APRA-E Project: NEXTCAR – Research Assistant/Intern

- Developed software for wireless V2V, V2C, V2I, and C2V communications using AMQ Protocol
- Intelligently redesigned routing topology for efficient, cycle-free, robust communication
- Developed ease-of-access tools for navigating the terminal
- Used Simulink, Python (pika module), RabbitMQ (message broker), Cohda DSRC (V2I transceiver)

Elec/Comp Learning Center Coach - Houghton, MI	Jan 2018 – May 2021
Embedded Systems Interfacing (EE4737) TA – Houghton, MI	Jan 2020 – May 2020
Hardware-Software Integration (EE3173) TA – Houghton, MI	Sept 2020 – May 2021
Electronics (EE3131) TA – Houghton, MI	Jan 2021 – May 2021

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Microcontrollers (Arduino, ESP)
- IBM DNG
- Quartus, Qsys, and AMP
- Algorithmic Design/Analysis
- Unix and Windows Development

- Embedded Programming (MSP)
- IAR Workbench
- Microsoft Office
- Software Testing
- CANalyzer